

CONTACT

• 010-2209671

farid.zaid96@gmail.com

20, Jalan Sutera 2/2, Taman Sutera, 43000 Kajang, Selangor

EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF TECHNOLOGY: INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY

2015 - Present

Universiti Teknologi PETRONAS Current CGPA: 3.09

FOUNDATION IN TECHNOLOGY

JAN 2014 - DEC 2014

Universiti Teknologi PETRONAS

Current CGPA: 3.19

MALAYSIAN CERTIFICATE OF **EDUCATION**

2012 - 2013

Royal Military College, Malaysia Result: 2A+ 3A 3A- 1B+

COMPUTER SKILLS

C++

Adobe Photoshop CS5 Pascal Microsoft Office Suite MIT Apps Inventor HTML, PHP, Javascript

MUHAMMAD FARID

UNIVERSITI TEKNOLOGI PETRONAS

BACHELOR OF TECHNOLOGY (HONS) INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY



farid.zaid96@gmail.com



6 010-2209671

ABOUT

I am an undergraduate student pursuing my Bachelor Of Technology (HONS) Information Technology from Universiti Teknologi PETRONAS. 3+ years of Computer Information Technology learning experience. I am very interested to learn more in hardware development, software development, web development and internet of things field of study.

CORE COMPETENCIES

Performance Analysis Fostering Teamwork Managing Change **Developing Others** Determination Innovative

Adaptable Quality Control **Problem Solving Result Orientation Analytical Thinking** Technical Skills

ACQUIRED SKILLS

COMMUNICATION & WRITING

English

Bahasa Melavu

Basic Mandarin

* * * * *

WORKING EXPERIENCE

PETRONAS TWIN TOWER VISIT OPERATION VOLUNTEER | SEPT 2015 - DEC 2015 & SEPT 2016 - OCT 2016

This department is operated by PETROSAINS Science Discovery Center. My job scopes in this department are helps the visitors if they have any inquiries about PETRONAS TWIN TOWER and guides the visitors in their guided tour until they reach at the Observation Deck at level 86.

TRAINING EXPERIENCE

MOBILE APPLICATION DEVELOPMENT WORKSHOP Participant | 2015

- learn how to build mobile application by using MIT apps inventor
- learn how to teach people in using MIT apps inventor

I am qualified to be a trainer of MIT apps inventor. I have been a trainer for these workshop or events:

- Mobile Application Training 3.0
- IT Outreach Camp (IT 101)

CO-CURRICULAR ACTIVITY

IT OUTREACH CAMP (IT 101)

TRAINER & ASSISTANT HEAD OF SPONSORSHIP DEPARTMENT | 6 - 8 JANUARY 2017

- teach students of MRSM Betong, Sarawak in how to build a mobile application and test their knowledge on what we have been teaching by doing a simple competition in making mobile application among the students
- · search for sponsorship for our event

C-SOC REGIONAL COMPETITION 2016

PARTICIPANT & COMMITTEE | TECHNICAL & PROMOTION AND PUBLICATION DEPARTMENT | 10 DECEMBER 2016

- participate in a regional hacking competition after my team and I have qualified and win 6th place in UTPHax 2016
- the Head of Technical Department and our job scope is setting up the network that are needed in this competition and make sure all the technical stuffs are in a good condition during the competition
- my job scope is making the mock cheque, bunting and certificate of this competition

NATIONAL INNOVATIVE SMARTPHONE CONTROLLER CONTEST 2016

PARTICIPANT | NOVEMBER 2016

• with an idea that was inspired by me, we manage to build a product that is called E-Charger as it is a way to control the overcharging problem in smartphone and we have won the Gold Medal Award for this product

KPMG CYBER CHALLENGE 2016

PARTICIPANT | NOVEMBER 2016

• in a team of four members, my team and I manage to get 12th place out of 60 teams in this hacking challenge that was conducted by KPMG Malaysia

UTP NATIONAL HACKING COMPETITION 2016

PARTICIPANT | OCTOBER 2016

• in a team of three members, my team and I manage to get 6th place and the Best Team in North Region in this hacking challenge and make us qualify for the C-SOC Regional Competition 2016

PROGRAM JALINAN MESRA KOMUNITI @ ROYAL BELUM

COMMITTEE | PROMOTION AND PUBLICATION DEPARTMENT | AUGUST 2016

• I has become one of the photographer in this event

DOTA 2 UTP CHAMPIONSHIP 2016

COMMITTEE | ACTIVITY AND GAMES DEPARTMENT | MAY 2016

• I has become one of the host to conduct the 5 vs 5 Dota 2 competition

UTP NATIONAL HACKING COMPETITION 2015

COMMITTEE | FOOD AND BEVERAGE DEPARTMENT | NOVEMBER 2015

• I have to search for tenders to provide food for participants and committees of this competition

MOBILE APPLICATION TRAINING 3.0

TRAINER & COMMITTEE | FOOD AND BEVERAGE DEPARTMENT | AUGUST 2015

• as the Head of Department, I have to deal with the management of UTP and distribute all task equally to all committees

FIRST LEGO LEAGUE MALAYSIA 2015

COMMITTEE | EVENT MANAGEMENT DEPARTMENT | MAY 2015

I have to guide the participant of this competition to the specific competition room all around UTP

REFEREES

ASSOC PROF DR MOHD FADZIL BIN HASSAN

DEANS OF CENTER FOR GRADUATES STUDIES UNIVERSITI TEKNOLOGI PETRONAS

mfadzil_hassan@petronas.com.my

012-3675199

ROSAZIZAN BIN ROSLI

SENIOR MANAGER OF UMW PETROPIPE LABUAN

mosazizan.rosli@umw.com.my

**** 017-9196606